We dedicate this film to
NCOs like Omer Halisdemir.
To officers like Harun Kilinç.
To specialists like
Yunus Emre Uçar as well as.
The Turkish Armed Forces
and all of it's selfless soldiers.
This is Black Sheep 44-1 Niner.
Bandits marked. Reference south.
Black Sheep 2, angels 15.
Alpha Check.
Affirm. Estimated mark 4 miles.
Everybody out of burners.
Mark clear.
Permission to splash target.
Break break, Black Sheep 44-1.
This is Turkish AWACS Güney.
NATO friendlies in sector.
Break break, Black Sheep 44-1.
This is Turkish AWACS Güney.
NATO friendlies in sector.
Stand by 2. Come in, Güney.
Operation near the mountain.
OPSEC may be compromised. Please comply.
THE MOUNTAIN II
As a part of the kuffar coalition.
Having interviewed civilians.
And filmed idolaters.
I regret...
Regret...
Nothing.
I regret nothing!
The world must know these animals...
Do it!
Do it you scum! Do it!
You think I would give you my fear?
Do it!
The wind
is intensity 2, from 3 o'clock.
Distance 800 meters.
A taut bow is pulled...
To unleash the arrow.
Ms. Balaban?
Ms. Balaban, are you alright?
Are you hurt anywhere?
- What?
- Are you hurt?
No.
Please come with us.
We're here for you.
Sir, we need to head to the village.
We are exposed here.
Mustafa, give me time.
Five minutes tops, sir.
Eşref, buy us time.
Drop anyone armed in the alleys.
Earman in the alleys.
- Who are you?
- Special Forces, ma'am.
Combat search and rescue.
Oguz, Bekir.
Find Ceyda's civilian outfit.
Baybars, gather mags.
We're leaving.
Where?
Home, Ms. Balaban.
We're going home.
Here we go again, into the shit...
Join me only if you want it.
I'll never be accepted.
My leg aches even when jacking off.
Do you want it or not?
Jacking off?
Bekir...
C'mon just drink.
Less talk more sips.
Whatever happened to that girl?
You know, the one you told me
about at the relay station?
Oh man, you remember that...
She got married two months ago.
We never had a girl whose voice
rang like toasted glass.
You're drunk again.
You know what? We never
really forget someone.
We carry lost ones behind our
backs like sacks of memories.
We're like porters, man.
We pray, we cuss, we endure.
But those memories prowl
in our heads like foxes.
The dead and lost loves are the same.
We only ever reminisce about them.
Sometimes, in my dreams,
I see Captain Yaşar.
I see his final glance at me.
There is worry there,
but not for himself, you know?
He's afraid for me instead.
What would he have said at this?
If he ever heard we were
signing up for Special Forces trials...
First he would lovingly pat our backs.
Then he'd tell a dirty joke.
After that he would
probably cuss us out.
Probably.
Oguz.
We're the guys Sergeant Kemal and he
died to let live. We need to be worthy.
Otherwise we're trash.
To the unforgotten.
Arif, what do you see?
Iraq, sir...
The land of betrayal and enmity.
We're 24 km southeast of the mountain.
They will be here soon.
What's our ammo status?
We gathered what we could
but they are all AK rounds sir.
These men were reinforcements.
Real assault troops are south.
We need to reach the landing
zone as soon as possible.
- Bekir?
- Yes, sir.
Get an AK, we can booby trap it.
Why just me?
Why?
My team was also there.
Why just me?
My cameraman Phillip,
producer Nechirwan could
have been here with us, alive.
Because they weren't Turks...
that's why you did nothing.
It is not that simple Ms. Balaban.
Ceyda will do. No need for Ms.
Don't worry, I won't keep reminding
you of your racist preferences.
Remind us if you like.
I can't endanger the lives of my men
for those who aren't Turkish citizens.
- Do you know who I am...
- Oh we do.
Your views, your articles, your
opposition, they don't concern us.
- A mission is a mission. Bekir?
- Yes sir.
You scout ahead with Oguz.
We leave from the rear with Ceyda.
We head for the villages 10 km west.
Keep your eyes peeled.
Ceyda wears my helmet and
the kevlar vest Eşref brought.
If she takes it off, make her wear it.
Are we all set?
How is your ear?
I have reconstruction surgery
in two weeks sir.
Are you two kidding me?
Just get your honorable discharge.
Why are you still in service?
One of you has a platinum shoulder.
The other one half lame.
What trials, what training?
Sir, if you only let us
explain the situation...
I don't think you understand.
We have no use for damaged men
who might risk their teams.
Say we put you in, what do
we do with your friend?
Is he going to cook behind enemy lines?
I'm just about to cuss.
What did you say?
- Selim.
- Attention!
- I will take it from here.
- Yes, sir.
At ease.
Units here are not about individual men,
but about cohesiveness.
If one man falters,
the entire team may fall.
That is why old wounds are important.
'The short-termer has no rifle,
and the other is Bekir.'
Yaşar's last words to me.
- Are your two years up?
- They will be in two months sir.
Bekir becomes a specialist,
myself a Lieutenant.
Yaşar was my classmate.
My friend.
If they had send us to you
instead of HQ,
I would gladly have died to avenge him.
You want me to throw the kids
he saved into the flames.
My answer is no.
They are not kids anymore sir.
One wakes up gasping in the night
to nightmares of Sergeant Kemal
whispering his wife's name as he dies.
Leyla.
The other wants to dedicate himself
to a cause for the first time.
They might be many things sir,
but they are not kids.
If they died to make us live,
then let us live, sir.
Let us make others live.
You have two months.
Prepare well.
The trials and classes will be hell.
Way to go!
There aren't real deserts you know.
They are all wind erosion.
Huh? Eurovision?
Man, use the internet once for
something other than porn.
Just kidding bro.
Here we are, alone again.
This is my fucking destiny.
My fate.
Snow, winter, desert, sand...
Death and Oguz.
I wish you would nag with the
Lt. Colonel nearby, just once.
Oh I'm sorry, 'sir'.
I mean I don't pull rank because
it's you.
Tell me, do you think it was worth
risking 7 national treasures for Ceyda?
Bekir Özbey, national treasure.
Answer me you dolt.
I don't know.
Well if you ask me she can
be a little more respectful.
Bekir...
662 Tamu Cizre, this is Storm Bringer.
- The package is safe, over.
- T-155's are ready sir.
We can illuminate the area, over.
Still undetected, no needs, over.
Copy that Storm Bringer, on standby.
Where are you from, Ms. Balaban?
Is this you tactic?
Excuse me?
The others are robots.
I'm a package.
Are you supposed to be the kind one?
I wish the soldiers I train would
hear of what you just said.
I believe this belongs to you.
Other than us, you can
photograph anything you like.
You don't have to be nice.
And you don't have to be grateful.
I'm not.
I know.
I'm from Milas.
They executed everyone, even children.
Sons of whores.
Where are we?
36-25 to 41-75.
These are Yezidi grasslands.
This is new sir.
2-3 hours.
They don't struggle during killing.
Fathers lie to their children so
that it's over quickly.
Otherwise they torture those who resist.
Pull nails... gouge eyes...
Their only fault is to exist.
According to their killers, Yezidi
are not human, but devilspawn.
Their sin is to have a religion
the others can't understand.
This is not our fight.
No sir. It's not.
Because this is no fight at all.
- Sir?
- Go ahead Arif.
They're coming.
Let them come.
We are death's lovers.
Take off your berets.
Take a look at them.
Are you here for those berets?
From the 200 selected NCO and
officers in these trials...
...only 20 will join active duty.
But why?
What is our nature?
Are we heroes? Warriors?
Legends?
If you're seeking such things,
you're in the wrong place gentlemen.
We are nothing.
Our aim is to be forgotten...
...unknown.
Our names won't be carved into stone.
They won't sing about us.
For if we gather fame,
that means we have failed.
Our nature is to utterly serve
the Turkish people.
We are death's lovers...
...and only us...
...because both suffering and fear of
her must stay away from our people.
If one day when you let out
your last breath...
...the only thing you see is
your blood...
...and the only thing you hear
is silence...
...know that you are not alone.
Those before you, those after
you, all of Special Forces...
...will die with you...
...and be reborn with you.
- One dies...
- ...a thousand rise!
- Good luck, gentlemen.
- Sir yes sir!
Oguz, they're coming. Oguz!
Bekir...
Oguz?
Oh they're here man. Oguz?
Shut up, stop using the comm.
You're gonna get us killed!
Hush damn it!
- Tamu Cizre.
- Your orders, sir.
Illuminate them.
Copy Storm Bringer.
Illuminating.
Arif.
The night births the moon.
To rise and fall.
Mecnun moans as his blood...
...joins beloved Leyla.
These men came from the west, Mustafa.
There were none west this morning.
662 Tamu Cizre.
This is Storm Bringer.
What do you see?
Veysel, it's me, Doan.
Your orders, sir.
Kurds are exhausted north.
They can't hold. The pincer has closed.
How many?
The jihadis are encircling the
mountain to shut off the border.
You need to hurry.
Sir, how many?
Two thousand.
Get out of there.
What does this mean?
This area is surrounded.
Such bad luck.
We're in the middle of total invasion.
Sir.
This truck works.
We can reach the climb to the mountain.
Won't Turkey send you reinforcements?
This is a clandestine operation.
Turkish soldiers are officially not here.
Only we can save ourselves.
The situation is deteriorating.
Those two thousand men, in order
to hide from American bombers...
...will climb the mountain.
We need to find safe shelter.
There is.
There is a place...
There is a place, gentlemen!
A dark place.
A place that will lend you
strength, even if you have none.
You've finished the obstacle track.
You think you're done for, but no.
Now, together, we discover that place.
You!
Bekir Özbey, Ankara. Your orders, sir!
- You're a wounded vet.
- Right leg, sir.
I don't care.
You ran the track, does it hurt?
It does sir.
I don't care.
You're tired, does it limp?
A little sir.
I don't care! Run!
Run Bekir, run! Go!
Sir, yes sir!
That pain will be honey
during missions, Bekir!
Your eyes will tear up!
Your teeth will ache!
But I'll make you find that dark place!
The mind is formed of gears, gentlemen.
It commands the body.
The mind which has nothing to lose...
...can't push the body.
Here's something to lose, Bekir!
I'll eliminate you!
Lungs, spleen giving up!
Platinum screws, whole body bankrupt!
But you can't go to that
dark place only for yourself.
Bekir Özbey, if you aren't here
in 30 seconds...
...I eliminate your friend Oguz too.
He'll back up right away...
Your creed, your race, the music you
listen to, your favorite food...
...doesn't matter one bit!
Only two important things, gentlemen!
Homeland... and the guy next to you!
You die and kill for these two things.
If need be, your friend will
cripple his leg once again...
...but he will never
let his friend down!
Your old wound will be a
privilege, Bekir.
Every day you'll get
electo-physical therapy.
You will weep from pain, understood?
Yes, sir.
You think it's over rookies?
On your feet!
Into the lake up to your chest.
Sponges will not touch the water.
We are here until dawn, guys!
Your body temperature will fall.
When the shivering starts
and suddenly stops...
...know that you are freezing.
Don't get wasted, get out and
be eliminated.
Gentlemen, we will check every
sponge in the morning.
One drop of water when squeezed,
and you'll still be eliminated.
Oh sir, thank you, but I'm not
really a tea guy.
I'd drink some Turkish coffee though.
- Wow sir, no tea for us?
- Come here and have some, Oguz.
Sir if you wouldn't mind, you can bring
it here. The water is beautiful.
Come here sir, we'll warm you up.
Looks like you want to run again Bekir.
No sir, I just want to warm up.
Love of the homeland will warm
you, Bekir!
You are thunderbolts, rookies!
You are avalanches!
Whirlpools!
The bottom of the sea...
...depths of the earth...
...even the highest place in the
skies...
...is your home!
You will be afraid!
Fear is good.
Fear will keep you alive.
But not fear of heights...
...because eagles don't fear heights!
♪ How the wicked bullet
pierced his brow ♪
♪ His black eyes suddenly frozen ♪
♪ Only her son's bloody beret in
her hands ♪
♪ Oh mother, I would lie if
I said he will come back ♪
♪ Beautiful mother, dear mother,
it's not easy ♪
♪ It's not easy ♪
♪ Never easy ♪
What is this place, exactly?
Tomb of an Akkadian king, named Sargon.
Take Baybars and Eşref.
You have command.
We need to shelter there.
Yes sir.
Baybars.
Everybody finish their meals.
We join them in ten minutes.
Why did they want you to rescue me?
Does it matter?
Throughout my career I've
written articles opposing you.
Good fucking job.
Bekir.
Forgive him.
Special Forces took him out of the
fight, but not the fight out of him.
It's alright. I'd prefer you
your thoughts.
Our thought, is our mission.
And that is to get Ceyda
Balaban, out of Iraq.
- That's all?
- It is.
So Turkey will idly watch
this barbarity.
Those who suffer here were once
a part of us.
If we warred for all our parts, we'd
need to drive tanks to Altai Mountains.
What happens here is not war,
it's a crime against humanity.
Am I supposed to shut up and remain
silently grateful because you saved me?
Nobody wants you grateful.
But you should respect those who
volunteered into this shit, for you.
You're right. But respect for you...
...and respect for the organization
you serve are different things.
Give me a break.
Go tell that to the sheep who lock up
soldiers and then declare them heroes.
Blood and life.
That's what we offer here.
Bekir, enough.
Bombardment will soon begin, pack up.
Eşref!
He can take care of himself, go!
C4. Basic Semtex 1A.
Find the fuse.
Found.
- No backup trigger.
- Same here.
We ready?
FG 1, this is FG 2.
The tomb is clear, waiting for you.
Not interested.
What?
Not interested in what?
In what you're doing. I don't care.
I'm here to buy books.
Since you are you prepared to
be this defensive...
Am I under attack? Never mind,
don't answer that, no need.
I really am not interested.
Do all guys who approach you
give up this easily?
Unless they are shameless, sure.
I have this theory.
In essence, all men are actually
invaders.
Women on the other hand, are castles.
One aims to conquer and occupy,
proving himself.
The other wants to remain secure
and repel the onslaught.
So romantic.
But then there are some invaders...
...so interesting and so original...
...that the castle decides...
...to open its gates without resistance.
And you think you're one of
these interesting invaders?
You aren't doing great, let me tell you.
Would you like to have some coffee?
I also have a theory.
That ultimately you are looking
for a nanny, and not a lover.
Possible.
That's not so enjoyable for
us women, though.
Why specifically Special Forces?
There was a feeling I had during combat.
An awareness.
A moment where the true value of
life just hit me.
Turtle.
- Turtle?
- I mean a turtle personality.
Because I'm green?
Think of a turtle.
Crossing the road.
It doesn't care about the cars.
It thinks the shell will protect it.
But in reality, it's fragile.
Can be crushed at any second.
Turtle personalities don't really
care about what happens to them.
A wise woman would stay away
from such a damaged man.
I should just get up and leave.
Why don't you?
How long until your first mission?
Assuming I pass the trials...
...five more years.
How long do you need me for?
Check it.
You said Akkadian...
...but face is Alexander the Great.
I guess I shouldn't be surprised
you're a history expert.
Somewhere my college professor
is laughing.
Load it.
Sargon was a king who lived
4000 years ago.
Successive civilizations built
on top of their ruins.
Sumerians, Egyptians, Persians,
Babylonians, Greeks.
All the way to our present day.
Some built tombs, some placed mosaics.
Some drank kymyz.
To you, all soldiers are noble.
But you see, all of those
civilizations also had soldiers.
In the end they fought, and killed
each other for more and more.
They still do.
Is that how you justify your
hate of the military?
By placing blame of war on only
soldiers?
Again.
We don't think all soldiers are noble.
Only those who serve their people.
What good will learning this do for me?
Hopefully nothing.
Have you ever killed someone?
How does it feel?
It's not a feeling.
It's a stain.
Get ready.
Sir, I'll carry you.
I will sir! I'll carry you!
Oguz, wake up! Oguz!
You'll take my rifle.
This is a dangerous place, Oguz.
When I'm about to fall asleep at night,
I always wake up and look around me.
I'm human too.
I feel fear as well.
One dies! A thousand rises!
Oguz?
The water's freezing. Are you alright?
Don't do this to yourself.
Come with me.
I'm okay here.
This training will devastate you.
You remember stuff you're supposed
to forget and internalize it. Don't.
When they saved us...
...they thought I did what I did
because of bravery.
As if I were defiant before the
sniper who was shooting at us.
That's a lie.
I was depleted.
I lost.
I just didn't want to leave
Bekir behind.
Wanting death is a weird thing.
Having it be your only escape.
You kind of want to fall in the dark.
The thought of it becomes sweet.
I still couldn't leave that mentality.
What if I died there?
What?
Not physically.
What if I can never regain my
enthusiasm or normality?
That is why I must go back and
face that moment once again.
That terror and awareness has become...
...the only thing that makes me happy.
The only thing that makes you happy?
I know, it sounds strange.
You'll immediately talk about
men, women and relationships...
...how you're hurt at this.
No, I won't.
You think you're so smart.
But being human
is not about ending fear.
It's about accepting them,
moving forward despite them.
I fear stuff too.
Like what?
Like catching cold tomorrow.
Up, up, up.
- What now?
- Get up.
Oh I'm sorry? I thought your only
happiness was awareness and terror?
You're something terrible too.
No thanks, I'm going to find myself a
normal guy. You can keep flailing.
- Nailing?
- I said flailing, idiot.
662 Tamu Cizre.
- Are we too high up?
- No, sir. Must be a jammer.
Keep trying.
662 Tamu Cizre.
Visual, sir.
What will they do to the women, Ceyda?
What do you think they'll do?
They are on our way, sir.
Don't get emotional.
If we ignore this too, I'm about
to lose all emotion anyways.
We can also head for the other peak.
What do we do, sir?
How long have you been hungry?
Seven, sir.
Thirst?
Two, sir.
Man, you guys are fucked.
How long have being awake, rookie?
Three, sir.
Quit the trials.
This life isn't for you.
Gentlemen, I got a big table
inside for all of you.
Brought some delicious food.
Like what you ask?
Buttered Iskender Kebap.
Lamb Ca kebap.
Ayran, tea, coffee.
Baklava. Both walnut and
pistachio baklava.
And of course we have what?
Water boys, we have water.
I had huge ice cubes brought for you.
When you drop them in, you will
hear them crackle, gentlemen.
All you have to do, when we ask,
is to tell us...
...the name on your piece of paper.
Lie down!
Yavuz.
Go get some grub.
Sir.
I'll cuss, sir.
Oh no, sir, he's going to cuss!
Maybe we should skip him?
This is torture training, skippy.
Cuss, sing, makes no difference.
Please sir, don't have him sing.
That will be the real torture.
Tell us the name on your piece
of paper, go eat hot food.
Sleep like a log. Let this
suffering end, Bekir.
This life is not for you.
The enemy will not offer you food.
They won't give you warm beds as
you give up!
They won't help with the pain!
Tell me.
Tell me buddy.
Tell me the name, let's end this.
♪ Ah, forgive me during nighttime
As the moon crosses the sky ♪
♪ Forgive me before dawn
Right when we break up ♪
♪ For you, are the rain to my deserts ♪
♪ You are the morning to my night ♪
♪ You are the comrade to my life ♪
♪ The blanket to my winter ♪
- Sir, he's approaching the record.
- He will pass it too.
35, 36.
38, 39, 40.
41, 42.
These guys were forged in fire.
They won't give up.
Sir, I feel so thirsty.
Can I have some more?
I am not Superman, bullets do affect me.
Baybars, what about you?
Me too sir.
I'm Superman sir. Got one on the
leg, then became a maroon beret.
Open your arms and run before us Bekir.
Become cover for us.
Sing Ankaran Turgut as you run.
Oh man, how I miss his songs.
Arif, your target?
3 o'clock, sir.
If it misses, the gasoline...
It won't miss.
Get ready for contact.
On three.
One.
On point with Bekir.
Two.
Three.
Fickle is the lover,
To make hearts bleed.
Wear your helmet!
Sniper!
Get down!
Why does the poet toil,
To weave the poem.
Are you alright?
Yes!
Alright, it's alright.
Don't be afraid.
You're safe.
It's over.
May God give you blessings.
May God repay your kindness
in abundance.
Amen.
Amen we say, oh Lord, as we open
our hands to your holy domain...
...let us not be without your grace,
let our hearts know contentedness.
Amen.
We believe there is no limit
to you mercy.
Your charity and will is infinite.
- Bless us with those, oh Lord.
- Amen.
You adore the good, those who repent.
Let us be able to reach you
as we ourselves repent, Lord.
Amen.
Oh master of all realms, oh
munificent one.
Lighten the unbearable loads on
our souls...
...do not let us be helpless, Lord.
Amen.
As we stand here today, in the funeral
rites of our beautiful Mine, bless her.
Give us, her friends, her brother
Mete, her father Veysel...
...and mother Ayşe strength
to bear the pain, oh Lord.
Defend our homeland, our people, our
flag, our sacred values oh God.
- Amen!
- El Fatiha.
My condolences, Veysel.
Do you need anything at all?
A leave perhaps?
I thought I knew death, sir.
Back in 94, General Osman and we
used to fly over dead bodies...
...in UH helicopters...
...we used to find out who died
where, with our noses.
Back then America would refuse
giving night vision to our birds.
We used to find our martyrs with nose.
I thought I knew death.
Now I know I didn't.
Turns out death...
...is waiting for my wife at the
door of the funeral home...
...as she washes my girl's dead body.
I waited.
I cried.
I cried for dresses she'd never wear.
I cried for fights we'd never have.
I cried for a life unlived.
If only she could love a man,
get married...
...have children.
When I woke up from the daydream, I had
punched the mortuary wall 20 times.
Blood, tears and water were everywhere.
The undertaker was bandaging my hand.
Three broken bones.
No need for a leave.
Just have them send painkillers.
We've eaten a third of our ammo.
We need to reach the LZ fast, sir.
We are surrounded. Tracks are
everywhere. Already engaged too.
We're pushing our luck.
Do you know what they first teach you
when you get Search and Rescue command?
Lying.
That's not what they literally say.
But it's the essence of it.
If morale is low nothing else matters.
You can't just tell the naked truth
to your men on days of casualties.
You have to build a lie.
Then you need to believe it yourself.
What kind of a lie?
A beautiful one.
That they'll be remembered after death.
How many men have died under my command?
I don't know.
23.
I always console myself that I would
always remember those 23 men.
But each passing day I forget
their faces a little more.
Peshmerga.
Pesheng.
**Kurdish**
How's your Turkish?
Better than your Kurmanji.
You're in bad shape.
I will give you morphine.
What's your name?
Çiya.
We aren't PKK, Turk.
We are Zerawani.
Tell me Çiya, what happened?
They sent us from íeqlawe.
Then DAESH invasion began.
We couldn't slow them.
How many were you?
How many men were you Çiya?
80.
Now, just 1.
Commander?
Those boys were entrusted to me.
Me.
Now they're food for this cursed
mountain.
Don't waste them on me.
You will need them yourself.
But don't leave me here.
Don't abandon me.
Do it.
Fire it on my heart.
End it.
Enough.
In God's name, enough.
Fire it, end it.
Enough.
My soldiers wait for me, commander.
They await me.
Right now you are marble.
Before your first mission we
will chisel your for 5 years.
History, geography, medicine, chemistry,
guerilla warfare, psychology...
...and languages will be your
curriculum.
You will either pass a difficult
education or again, be eliminated.
You're screwed, Bekir.
Because you are the last castle.
Men with knowledge as well as bravery...
...those who do not bow to emotion...
...first to go in, last to come out.
You will save lives more
than you will take them.
This will be a hard life.
Maybe a short one.
Your families will share you with us.
They will be happy with the crumbs.
You'll miss many graduations,
anniversaries and weddings.
On your child's birthday...
...bullets will rain atop some mountain.
Still, it will be worth every second.
This love, is such a love
that even if it consumes you...
...kills you...
...you will never let go.
Welcome amongst us, brothers.
Sir, Çardakl1 has visual.
It looks so green.
I guess Sinjar's only stream
flows there.
Five minutes rest, then we move on.
Copy that.
Are you Turuk?
Excuse me?
Turuk?
Yes, we are Turks.
I'm also Turuk.
Çardakl1 is also kin.
They are all Turuk.
Çardakl1 is a Turkmen village.
We are Turuk alright.
Wafer?
Not this time.
Looks clean.
Just some civilians.
Around 30 to 40.
Where's the LZ?
Ahead, 100 meters lower altitude.
We need to call the T-70s sir.
They'll just about make it.
I can see Turkey from here.
What's your name?
Enegül.
I'm Bekir, Enegül.
That is Oguz.
I tried talking, she doesn't respond.
They carved nasheeds on her back
with a knife.
Sons of whores.
Then again, that only insults
the whores.
These are the realities you
still ignore.
This time, those who suffer
aren't arabs or kurds either...
...they are Iraqi Turks.
At least they will live.
Here, in this barbarity...
How does one live?
100 men, against 1000. How do they live?
This has no simple answer, gentlemen.
Is there a historical precedent?
Yes.
There are the Carthaginians.
Under Hannibal's command.
He did something similar at Cannae.
Naturally, the truth is
we need to examine the english theorist
B.H. Liddell Hart and his concepts.
During this battle, Romans were,
as always, too confident...
...86 thousand men...
You know what I miss?
...in three main columns, they
attacked with the middle strongest.
Fist-fighting you.
I wish I could just tussle once
more before you became my superior.
You're seriously crazy, man.
Bekir, Oguz, what's going on?
Sir, our friend Bekir here
wants to fight me one last time.
You fucking rat.
According to Hart's doctrine
How do 10 men fight against 100?
Answer it properly, go out during
the break, and beat each other up.
I allow it.
Sir, 1000 people will always crush 100.
Reality of numbers.
The only way to win, according
to Hart is to fight indirectly.
How, explain that too.
To focus on the vulnerable joints using
any trick and advantage possible.
Oh yes.
Our final fight.
The closing of an era.
A clean punch to the face wins.
What's the matter bro?
Scared of two?
May he who fears you, become you.
Come on shithead.
Come.
You're learning something. Come.
You alright?
You alright man?
Dude... you indirect warfare shit.
Who ever hits the nose?
Sorry man, not intentional.
I'm not Emin Boztepe.
Stop, don't stand.
Look up.
I fell in love with a girl.
We met the other day.
I think she likes me.
100 billion galaxies.
In each one, 100 billion stars,
countless planets.
And a girl likes Bekir.
She might be the woman I marry.
What the shit?
You're serious.
Way to go Bekir. Live that life.
How does one live a life?
Where the cloud casts a shadow,
that's the LZ, sir.
Looks like my hometown.
Do they have 50 cal echoes in
Bilecik too?
You don't know our girls.
Greetings.
Well met.
Are you Turkish soldiers?
- We are.
- Prepare qelyanalti, move it.
Qelyanalti?
What is that?
Afternoon breakfast.
Would be rude to refuse, right?
I agree.
Only fighter left in our village
is Boran.
Go speak to him.
- Welcome.
- Well met.
How many in this village, Boran?
25 adults, 15 children.
I'm the only one who
can carry a weapon, sir.
Gentlemen, rest without
bothering anyone..
Last stop before returning home.
You can rest in my home. Come.
Don't stay out. Come in.
Thanks, we are being a burden.
Don't you mention it commander.
The children here dream
of becoming Turkish soldiers.
We grow up with your tales.
- Your Turkish is great, Boran.
- I went to school in Gaziantep.
Before the war my father
used to import from Turkey.
The cobblestones on the village
square were his goods.
After he died we never got to finish.
If you don't mind me asking,
what happened your leg?
When those animals attacked
Talafar three years ago...
...we went to defend as a family.
I got one on the knee.
Commander, these lands were
the most fertile around Sinjar.
Wheat and fruit used to grow here.
After the war all were ruined.
Ottomans used to called
this place Turkmenreach.
Nothing to reach anymore.
We're surrounded. Like an island
on a sea of arabs and kurds.
Storm Bringer...
662 Tamu Cizre.
This is Storm Bringer.
Our new call sign, 923 Mountain.
Mountain, your signal is weak,
but copy that.
662 Tamu Cizre.
Mountain standing by.
Mountain, this is Wolf. Veysel?
I am here, sir.
Terrorists have crushed both the Iraqi
army and the kurds, the region is falling.
Their main battalion, 100 strong are
pillaging towards the last village.
Are you ready for extraction?
Which village?
Çardakl1. They arrive tomorrow noon.
Confirm the LZ, and get out
before dawn. Over.
I know commander.
It's alright.
Let us see you off unharmed,
that alone is enough.
- Lt. Colonel, this is a Shia village.
- I know.
Will you listen to me one minute?
Veysel!
They will kill everyone here.
Our mission is not to defend them.
- The mission isn't the issue here.
- The mission is the entire issue!
My own feelings and desires are
of no consequence.
The mission is the only issue.
In your world, your sense of
responsibility means idealism.
An altruistic dream of helping everyone.
In mine it's to keep my men
alive, whom I love like family...
...these brave, few men.
The entire issue is the mission.
No, sir.
The issue here, is
what bravery really is.
Bravery is not killing the enemy, or
defending borders drawn on a map.
There is only one righteous
reason for bravery in war.
And that is defending the innocent.
That war is coming commander.
That war is coming here.
Does this village deserve it?
Do these people deserve that fate?
Say something.
Enegül come here.
Come, dear.
Tell her.
Tell her so she knows.
Say "We're leaving".
Say "There won't be a single living
person here, tomorrow afternoon”.
What will they do to this girl, sir?
Tell her, so she knows.
Tell her!
If courage is leaving this girl, and
all the villagers to their fate...
...I would rather be a coward.
You can keep on being brave.
“Sir”? What are you doing here?
It was crowded, I wanted some fresh air.
What are you yourself doing out?
You're a married man now.
I was looking for you, dumbass.
C'mon, it was my mother's dying
wish, We have to make my dad dance.
C'mon.
Where is Ece, by the way?
We broke up.
Why man?
No idea.
I guess 2 years with me,
is like 20 years with you.
You know, I don't have many friends.
Actually I only have one.
Thank God though, I get to
observe this one idiot.
This guy thinks too much, Oguz.
More he thinks, more he fucks up.
He thinks he's alone.
But he ain't.
He needs to know this.
- This friend of yours?
- Exactly.
I'll tell him, if I see him.
Bro, they told me a ring might
cause problems during a jump.
We came up with this solution.
Respect, man.
3 years ago you said you'd get married.
Here we are and you're getting married.
This is how we live, I guess.
Learn by falling and getting back up.
I wish you the same.
Me?
Get up come on. I need to watch
you ruin this dance, move it.
Me? Not a chance.
I'll order you and you'll fucking do it.
C'mon.
You know what?
I beat you up so good that day,
I kinda miss it now.
How quickly you forgot 3 years ago.
I popped your nose open.
- Oh really?
- Yes really, move.
- Let's see how you do in Ankara.
- Game on.
Is Turkey pretty sister Ceyda?
Dawn will break Enegül, go to sleep.
Sister Nabat tell us. You went there.
The soil is not orange like it is here.
Ashen and green.
There is cold and warm.
Dew falls on flowers each
morning, without harming them.
Their mountains have waterfalls.
Their peaks aren't bald like ours.
They have it all.
All the good, all the bad.
When you walk in autumn,
your feet may be wet or dry.
A bird may shit or land on you.
Are their birds pretty?
They are.
Storks fly all around.
Falcons hunt lesser birds on hills.
Skylarks nest on city roofs.
Their cities are like fields.
Antep, 0stanbul, Ankara.
Buildings until the horizon.
Will we go one day?
We will, Enegül.
We will.
Go to sleep.
Sir.
Bekir and Arif are on sentry.
Others are resting.
Cizre will send the T-70 at dawn.
You will be a good officer, Oguz.
Despite me.
20 years from now...
...hundreds of men will look to
your words for everything...
Some of them will be troopers,
natural born soldiers.
Others young and foolish.
But all of them will follow your
example, Oguz.
If you show wisdom and awareness,
they will be wise and aware...
...if you show loyalty and bravery
they'll grow to be loyal and brave.
But above all...
...those under your command will
live and die...
...by your decisions, Oguz.
And then one day...
...you'll have to decide between
what's right and the mission.
The right thing is the mission, sir..
What's right, is the right thing, Oguz.
I've ignored many right things
for missions.
Back when we were your age
we served southeast with Yaşar.
We were both born and raised
in Eskişehir.
But if you asked us the city we
were from, we'd say í1rnak.
Not because of time stayed there...
...but because of our souls we spent.
If you only knew the friends we
had to lose for missions.
Seven years ago, Captain Yaşar...
...caught Bekir and I cussing at
each other once again.
He'd warned us 20 times by then.
Seeing that we were hopeless he
assigned a latrine to each...
...and forbid us using any other.
“You will clean your respective
shits every single day” he said.
He had this smile on his face.
He was smiling because they'd given
us the same punishment back in 88.
We became so polite within a week.
He was my Bekir, Oguz.
My best friend.
I chose the mission again
and couldn't make it in time.
He died because of me.
What would you do?
Sir, I...
...my head says we need to get out.
This has no end and numbers never lie.
True.
But my heart, sir...
...it's trying to fool me.
Says we can't abandon villagers
to murder.
Maybe, there's a chance that...
...we defend this place and live...
...then look back and say that
as Turkish soldiers...
...we did the right thing
as well as our duty.
Commander, what is going on?
All the village children have boarded.
Time for the unruly one.
- I won't go.
- You're the mission, Ceyda.
I'll do something, sir. I can be of use!
No. You returning, is not
open to discussion.
Just promise me one thing.
You will not speak of this.
You will not write it.
It will be a secret forever.
Why?
We are nothing.
Shadows. What we do must not be known.
Promise me.
I promise!
Open it when you arrive.
071 Wolf, this is Mountain.
Mountain, this is Wolf.
Your orders were clear!
Why is Falcon-1 not carrying you?
What the hell are you doing Veysel?
Sir we've delivered Ceyda.
But they had to leave early
due to the coming storm.
What storm, Veysel?!
Sir, I will consult my team
one by one, just to be sure.
Master Sergeant Mustafa Sahin.
I concur with my commander.
Staff Sergeant Arif Sayar.
I agree, sir.
First Lieutenant Oguz.
The weather is terrible, sir.
Sergeant Baybars Yücel.
I concur, sir.
Specialist Bekir Özbey.
Likewise sir.
Master Sergeant Eşref Çullu.
A storm is coming, sir.
Sir, the entire team concurs.
We'll try again tomorrow morning.
Veysel.
Your orders, sir.
Weather deterioration noted.
We are standing by.
May God help you all. Over.
In 1950 we used to say 'Iraqi Turks'.
Then suddenly we were forced
to call them Turkmen.
For us, land to be defended,
is land where our people live.
These villagers are our people.
- Eşref, you have it with you?
- Always, sir.
- Baybars?
- Your orders, sir.
Go, raise it on the village peak.
Today, this place is homeland.
This is not an American film.
Last minute air support won't
clear out those hundred men.
Mustafa.
Everything is here sir.
4 mags per rifle.
I got two rockets, for emergencies.
I can rig the C4's for remote
detonation is I crack a comm.
The village also has some gasoline.
If I break the DskH rounds...
...fill the shells and powder
within gas jugs as shrapnel...
Good. Divide all the benzene and
paraffin equally.
Oguz, explain.
There are two routes into the village.
The mosque path and the school path.
The mosque path is wider
but we got a choke point here.
This is the joint. Vehicles
must cross here.
We can use it.
I can rig a killbox with the C4's.
Two on each side of the road.
- Will take care of every truck.
- Then what?
No IED will kill 100 men.
We're going to need man to man
engagement if they slip in.
I just wish we had a guardian angel.
We send you up.
Always wanted to be a muezzin as a kid.
- Why didn't you do it?
- They said I had a horrible voice.
If they reach iron sights I'm fucked.
Need someone to keep the mosque clean.
- Boran can you do this?
- Say die, and I'll die, sir.
How do we position sir?
You, Mustafa, Oguz and I, we're
the vanguard.
After we collect our blood toll
at the bottleneck...
...we come here, to point green,
to you and Mustafa.
'Baybars Cocktail'.
Yücel Cocktail.
Molotov was his surname.
They must never know our real numbers.
We need someone to run around,
carrying ammo to displacers.
Veysel Commander?
Let me help.
The battle makes the warrior.
No mercy for those who try
to take this village.
You will make every invader crawl.
They will curse the day they
first took a step here.
They won't fear death, they'll fear us.
Village flank is the only weak
point. Where the school faces.
How many rounds do you have left?
300.
I'll be stingy.
- What is this place?
- Coalhouse.
It has a shelter under it.
Bring remaining civilians here.
This place falls, the village falls.
The Last Castle.
Sir. This is not the Last Castle.
We are.
No matter what keep the door closed.
Sir, please. Ceyda is gone.
If you would only allow it.
Keep the vox on so I can hear.
Just the initials.
And you can't ask me.
Go ahead then.
Well, I was just a kid
back then, 15 or 16.
Her initial was “E”.
She was 3-4 years older than I.
You know how you look at
something disgusting and cringe?
That's how she looked at me, like shit.
Turns out she liked me.
Then she invites me to drink lemonade.
I swear, sir, next thing I know
I open my eyes in her bedroom.
Somehow, it really happened.
For 11 seconds.
A.
From Sar1yer.
We had dated for a year.
I took her to a romantic dinner.
She was pretty scared.
As if I'd dump her and she'd have
no value after we made love.
But that's not what happened.
We dated for another 1.5 years.
Then she dumped me.
Mine was also a girlfriend. Z.
And?
That's all you need to know rookie.
Sheesh.
It's going to be pretty hard for Sergeant
Mustafa to remember 60 years ago.
F.
She was singer.
A singer?!
In a tavern.
Met her on the first day of
rookie leave.
Seeing my haircut, she thought I
was an officer.
I didn't tell otherwise.
Then, in a couple of months
I gathered my courage...
...and declared my love.
Oh God.
It was the 80's. Everybody was romantic.
F was an incredible woman.
She had breasts the size of my head.
That woman was like a film star
and a diva rolled into one.
I wonder where she is now.
I was 19.
Had a two year girlfriend.
We were into each other,
but could never be alone.
Couldn't convince past second base.
Anyways, she had this best friend.
That girl invited me to help
with homework.
B.
She seduced me a little.
I was a teen so I couldn't resist.
Well after my girl learned,
of course she dumped my ass.
Wow, wow, wow.
You see sir...
...this scoundrel...
should have been eliminated.
Funny thing is, they're still besties.
I'm a classic guy.
Sebahat. My first and only love.
She was the beauty of Akçaabat.
We got hitched a day before deployment.
Couldn't wait since something
might happen to me.
Next day I was on a convoy to
Kerşan camp.
Suddenly an RPG hit our Unimog's
rear tire.
Two died that very second.
PKM rounds bouncing everywhere.
Then I realize, I'm shaking.
I think I'll never see Sebahat again.
I accept it. You know how people
feel, 'nothing will happen to me'...
...this was the moment it ended.
A sergeant with shrapnel sticking out of
his jaw screams at us to remain calm...
...he puts in a cassette. Rock music
begins playing in the vehicle.
Outside ricochets keep rhythm..
Suddenly I begin enjoying it.
I realize I'm probably going insane.
You were a kid back then Eşref.
Frankly sir, I still got the
same feeling.
Only now, I never shake.
I'll find Sebahat even if I die.
- Visual!
- It's time, gentleman.
Arif, talk to me.
Battalion.
200 plus change. 8 tactical Hiluxes.
And one Abrams.
Abrams?
More good news.
- What's the formation?
- Two columns, sir.
Infantry ahead and rear.
Classic Saddam.
Five minutes.
Fear is good.
You'll run faster.
They have a tank!
But we have a Bekir.
Eşref, do what you do best.
And if you get exposed earman,
know that I watch over you.
- Bekir?
- Ready sir.
Come, all of you.
Wear this.
Would this stop a bullet, sir?
No. But it will stop ricochets.
Take cover. Over there.
They're approaching the chokepoint.
Arif, shrink your profile.
Brave die once, cowards thousands.
Channel 4. When you press it.
One. Two.
Three.
Four.
Now.
Why yell on a mountain?
To defy fate.
Flanks!
Move it!
Baybars! We can't hold this tank!
Run to the chokepoint!
Boran, get ready!
Arif, they're leaking in!
Bekir, back! Covering fire!
You're doing good.
Press the comm. Say the mosque is clean.
Say it like us.
The mosque is clean.
You again?
I can't even die alone?
- Two.
Two.
Baybars, where's my SMAW?!
Sweet roses blossom.
So the bees taste.
Roses pinned to chests.
To wither in time.
Arif.
Arif, get down!
Load up!
Arif, move!
- Arif, come in, Arif.
- They are in the village, sir.
Arif, we need to head to the
Last Castle. Get down.
Sir. The flank is falling.
On our way, Baybars.
Guys, fall back. We're right behind you!
Sir, I need to cover you.
- Mustafa.
- Sir.
The other day my son asked
"Dad are you a hero?".
What did you say?
I said I was not...
...but that I served under one.
Go!
Humans grow from the cradle.
To lie sleep in the grave.
Cover me!
Arif, how many do you see?
10 sir.
9.
Arif, you know my son, Rüzgar.
Of course I do sir. Handsome
like his dad.
Arif commander!
Boran!
- Hang in there buddy!
- I'm good, sir.
Rüzgar.
He will be my ward, sir!
Heroes gladly fall.
To protect their homeland.
One dies,
a thousand rise!
Arif, sitrep.
Eşref here sir.
Boran...
- Boran what?
- He's critically wounded.
Get out of there now.
- Bring Arif and the others.
- Yes sir.
- Bekir?
- Huh?
Thanks.
What, why?
Just, thanks.
I ain't used to this, scrub.
I'd expect daft history lessons
from you.
Huns, Ithiopans, Hittites and stuff.
- Ethiopian.
- What?
They are called Ethiopians.
That's more fucking like it.
Let's go.
- Eşref!
Eşref!
Don't.
Where'd it come from?
Shield.
What?
Make me your shield.
Eşref, I'm won't leave you here.
I can't feel my legs.
Use your head, Arif.
Make me your shield.
Come on.
4 o'clock.
Tell Sebahat.
I know, you'll find her.
Are you excited Bekir?
A little, sir, mostly because I get
to have a stubble after today.
You already know Baybars,
your classmate.
Everybody can do everything in MAK 8.
But we also have specialists among us.
Arif is our marksman,
Baybars will be heavy weapons.
Earman is infiltration.
Why do they say Earman?
If Eşref likes you, maybe one
day he'll tell the tale, Bekir.
Don't worry, nobody likes him.
Sir?
Why do we fold each other's parachutes?
So that you remember.
No man is responsible for himself only.
We always take care of each other first.
We ready?
Did you fold it properly?
Can't recall really.
Eşref?
Sir, they're encircling us.
Everybody load up.
Last!
Last.
Nabat, I'll help you to the shelter.
The battle makes the warrior, commander.
Oguz, wake up. Oguz!
Bekir!
One. One, two, three.
No!
Sir!
Sir.
I had a daughter Ceyda.
If she had lived I'd want her to
be like you.
With heart, knowledge, defiance.
I'd want criticizing the country
and the military.
The state, and the people too.
I'd want her uncovering our faults.
Just as long as she had love.
Love for the country and all its faults.
If you want to honor us...
...just love, Ceyda.
Remember the good things...
...our banter...
...brotherhood and the laughter.
Remember the football match.
Bekir.
Tell them my last command was to
extract all remaining villagers.
They won't refuse.
Oguz.
Don't forget.
The reason...
...don't forget it.
We've laid out all the plans
from HQ, sir.
Normally they ransom, but not now.
Ceyda put the yezidi on the news...
...they'll execute her.
It will take at least a week for them
to move south of Raqqa to the mountain.
We need to make good use of that week.
Why are we saving this woman?
She's a journalist who built
a career on criticizing us.
Being a Turk used to have some meaning.
- Still does, sir.
- Does it?
Does it, still?
They will behead a Turkish woman
and record it on camera.
The world will watch.
Beyond all duties, we soldiers
have a moral duty.
To put our life and our existence
on the line for the benefit...
...of all of our people, and stand
with them against any enemy.
She can hate us...
...or love us, makes no difference.
Our duty is absolute to our people.
That responsibility is why you exist.
It's why you're coming with us.
Gentlemen.
This is your first MAK 8 operation.
The time has come.
Indeed it has.
Time to let live.
Synced, corrected, and fixed by
H@w-to-kiLL @subscene.com.
-- WAIT ! THERE'S MORE -
Sir, through pass!
- Let do dammit.
- C'mon Oguz!
- Penalty!
- No it was nothing.
- What happened?
- Penalty.
What penalty sir?
Sheesh.
Bekir, don't offend a superior officer.
Aw sir, this here is
peer pressure from rank.
I used to be a civilian too!
Sir, you already gave us
this half-lame...
If you're all going whine,
let's stop playing.
You already have Baybars as keeper.
Aww, poor officers are sad.
It's alright sir. Win the game.
Get used to how officers are, Bekir.
They got the easy life.
- You too Brutus?
- Oh, didn't see you here, sir!
Well this has to stop.
I'm forming MAK 11.
NCOs only!
C'mon move!
We can do this!
♪ Still lots of places to go to ♪
♪ They'll never forget us here ♪
♪ We'll sing a folk song and leave ♪
♪ We've existed by loving, being loved ♪
♪ Sometimes fighting, dying, rising ♪
♪ Baked in an oven of meaning ♪
♪ We adore wise beauties and leave ♪
♪ We leave after paying all dues ♪
♪ We leave singing a song that endures ♪